utmb.edu 2001-10-19

# The University of Texas Medical Branch

**Privacy Statement  
****The University of Texas Medical Branch**

This privacy statement is applicable to [www.utmb.edu](http://www.utmb.edu/) and the public web sites directly created and maintained by the University of Texas Medical Branch in Galveston, Texas (UTMB). The following statement applies to the public and addresses the types and use of information gathered on the university’s web sites.

UTMB does not collect personally identifiable information about individuals except when individuals intentionally provide such information in a question, transaction, on a web form or other web-based communication sent to the university. Personally identifiable information sent to UTMB, such as an email message requesting information on a health topic, may be seen and addressed by staff for the purposes necessary to serve a message sender’s needs. It will not be sold or otherwise transferred to unaffiliated third parties without a visitor’s explicit consent or unless required by law.

UTMB may collect non-personal information—items such as date & time, a visitor’s web browser and version, the pages visited and the referring site—to perform statistical analyses of user trends and interests and to generate general reports based on this information, ultimately to better serve the users of this resource. This non-personal information is stored in server logs and again, will not be sold or otherwise transferred unless required by law

Users also should be aware that non-personal information and data may be automatically collected through the use of "cookies," small text files a site can use to recognize repeat visitors and enhance a user's access to and use of a site. Generally, cookies work by assigning visitors a unique number that has no meaning outside a specific site. Cookies are not programs that go onto a user’s system and damage files. Information that UTMB may collect or store in cookies is used for internal purposes only and is not sold or shared. Most web browsers also give users the ability to decline any "cookies" they may be offered by UTMB or others; browser "Help" files offer more information on this feature.

Additionally, users should be aware that when they voluntarily disclose personally identifiable information (e.g., user name, e-mail address) on the public bulletin boards, discussion groups or in the chat areas of UTMB sites, that information and any electronic "conversation" can be collected and used by non-UTMB parties.

Likewise, electronic mail and other Internet communications are not always secure against interception. UTMB has security measures and practices in place to help protect a visitor’s privacy and prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of information sent to the university.

It is possible that some web pages at UTMB may collect information about visitors and use that information for purposes other than those stated above. When this is the case, the details of the data collection and use will be spelled out via a distinct "privacy statement" link on the respective site.

Please address any questions about UTMB’s privacy policy and practices, or use of this web site, to [www@www.utmb.edu](mailto:www@www.utmb.edu). Or, write to the university via the postal service at UTMB Public Affairs, 301 University Boulevard, Galveston, TX, 77555-0802.

_

This policy is effective August 14, 2000. UTMB reserves the right to modify this policy by notifying users of the existence of a new privacy statement. This statement and the policies outlined are not intended to and do not create any contractual or other legal rights in or on behalf of any party.

_

_Employees of UTMB should refer to_http://www2.utmb.edu/is/security_frame.htm, _which outlines the university’s internal policies and employees’ specific responsibilities related to the use and protection of information resources. _
